status.net 2019-09-01

# 

#### Effective: May 25, 2018

It’s important to for us to ensure transparency in how we treat your information, and this privacy policy (“Policy”) will help you understand how we collect and treat your data.

The defined terms in this Policy have the same meaning as in our Terms of Service, which you should read carefully as soon as you start using the Services. The “Services” means the online productivity tool Status, Website https://status.net, and all associated services.

The Services involve the collection and handling of data, submitted by users to the Services (“Customer Data”), for example text, link, graphics, photos, videos, or other data, as well as personal information (“Personal Information”) which is information about an identifiable individual, e.g. a user’s name, email address, and time zone.

We will limit collection of Personal Information to what is reasonably necessary to provide and improve the Services and to which is reasonably necessary for the purposes consented to by you.

 **Personal Information and Customer Data** we collect:

  *  **account and profile information** including name, username, email address;
  *  **content** you submit or post to the Services including images, videos, texts;
  *  **communications** : when you communicate with us via email, through the Services, or otherwise, and when you use the Services to communicate with others, we automatically store a copy of your communications;
  *  **surveys and promotions** : if you participate in our surveys or promotions, we will collect the information you provide to us;
  *  **information about use** of the Services, including type of device, browser type and language, requested urls, ip address, mobile carrier, referring urls;
  *  **information from other platforms** : the Services may receive information about you from third-party platforms. If you choose to sign-up for the Services through Google or similar platform, you will be asked to share certain information with us as identified by those third-party platforms.

We may also use technologies such as cookies including both session-based and persistent cookies or similar technologies such as single-pixel gifs and web beacons to record log data, which helps us provide, protect and improve the Services. You can set your browser to not accept cookies, however, this may limit your options to use the Services.

The Services may collect Personal Information and Customer Data **when you** :

  * register to use the Services;
  * use the Services;
  * contact our support team;
  * visit the website status.net.

We collect Personal Information and Customer Data  **for the following purposes** :

  * to provide and improve the Services;
  * to communicate with you regarding your use of the Services;
  * to personalize your experience as part of our provision of the Services;
  * to enhance the security and safety of the Services for you and other users;
  * to assist on technical support issues and to verify your identity;
  * to better understand how our customers are using the Services and improve the Services;
  * to develop new tools, products, or services for you;
  * to process data, including the engagement of third-parties and providers, to provide or improve the Services;

The purposes listed above are a reasonably necessary part of your relationship with us.

We **share** Personal Information and Customer Data **with third parties** in the following ways:

  * We do not rent or sell your personal information to third parties;
  * We share Personal Information and Customer Data with other users of the Services:  

    *  **Public feed** (if feed admin made it public in Settings): though the Services others may find and view your profile and activity including texts and images you posted. Feed admin can customize a feed to set up whether non-participants of that feed may view it. We cannot control the Services visitors' use of any information feed owner choose to make available publicly.
    *  **Private feed** (if feed admin did not make it public in Settings): other users who are participants of the same feed may view your profile and activity in that feed including texts and images you posted. We cannot control the Services users' use of any information you posted.
  * Investigations: we may investigate and disclose Personal Information and Customer Data, as permitted by applicable law, when we have a good faith belief that such investigation or disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) comply with legal process and satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request (including a search warrant, subpoena, statute, judicial proceeding); (b) prevent, investigate, or identify possible wrongdoing in connection with the Services and enforce compliance with Customer Terms of Service or User Terms of Service; (c) protect against imminent harm to our rights, reputation, property, or that of our visitors, users, or the public.
  * We may share Personal Information and Customer Data with third-party service providers to permit such parties to provide services that help us with our business activities, including data analytics, customer support, payment processing, or providing, maintaining and improving functionality of the Services. We may share Personal Information and Customer Data with third parties to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, technical issues.
  * We do not store your credit card details: if you pay for the Services by credit card, your credit card details will be encrypted and stored by a PCI-DSS Level 1 compliant payment processor to automatically bill your credit card.
  * We may share Personal Information and Customer Data if we become involved in a merger, a potential or actual acquisition, joint venture, assignment, transfer, or other disposition of all or any portion of our business. In these cases, their use will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

#### Customer has control over Customer Data

Customer provides the Services with instructions on what to do with Customer Data, for example Customer may provide us with instructions to completely delete all Customer Data. Customer may add or remove additional user accounts, manage access permissions, download, modify or delete texts, images, files, and other information collectively submitted by users within a Workspace. These instructions may result in the modification, access, disclosure, or deletion of Customer Data. If you have questions or concerns about how our Customer (your Workspace owner) treats Customer Data, consult them for their policies.

#### We take steps to protect Personal Information and Customer Data

We take various steps to protect the Personal Information and Customer Data by making reasonable security arrangements to prevent misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, disposal or similar risks to the data.

If we use third-party providers for storing Personal Information and Customer Data, we ensure those providers comply with US-EU Safe Harbor Framework, PCI Level 1, SOC for Security, and Security Management Standard ISO 27001.

Automatic rotational backups of data are performed regularly.

We use 256-bit SSL encryption to protect data in transfer between your computer and the servers.

It is your responsibility to keep your password to the Services safe. Please immediately change your password or notify us at support@status.net as soon as possible if you become aware of any misuse of your password.

#### Your rights under GDPR (European Economic Area)

In some regions such as European Economic Area you may exercise certain rights regarding Personal Information and Customer Data, including the right to access, verify the accuracy, correct, receive, update, obtain the erasure of your personal data, object to the processing of your personal data, or withdraw your consent to collect and process your personal data. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your personal data conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.

Any requests to exercise your rights must be directed in writing to our Privacy Officer at po@status.net. These requests can be exercised free of charge and will be addressed within one month. We may ask you to verify your identity in order to help us respond efficiently to your request.

#### International transfers of personal data

In order to provide you with the Services, Personal Information and Customer Data will be transferred to and processed in Canada and USA, or any other country where our corporate affiliates and service providers operate. Data protection laws differ among jurisdictions, and USA and these other jurisdictions may not provide the same level of protection for personal data as your jurisdiction of residence. If you are from EEA (European Economic Area) and we transfer your personal data to countries outside of the EEA, we will protect your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy wherever it is processed.

#### Retention of Personal Information

We retain Personal Information only for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes for which we are processing Personal Information, or as needed to comply with our legal obligations and enforce our agreements, and then we securely delete Personal Information. You can cancel your account at any time by sending a request to support@status.net. We may ask you to verify your identity in order to help us respond efficiently to your request. Customer Data that have been shared with others through status.net feeds may remain visible after you have closed your account. Please note, we do not control information or content that others have copied out of the Services.

#### Children

The Services are not directed to children under 13 and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information and Customer Data from anyone under the age of 13. In the event that we learn that we have collected Personal Information or Customer Data from someone under the age of 13 without verification of parental consent, we will take appropriate steps to delete that information. If you become aware or believe that we might have any data from or about a child under 13, please contact us immediately at po@status.net.

#### You can opt-out of email communications

We may send notifications and information to you via email. Our emails always contain an “Unsubscribe” link.

#### Additional information:

Any inquiry, complaint or question regarding this Policy must be directed in writing to our Privacy Officer at po@status.net.

#### Changes to Policy:

A current version of this Policy is always available on our website https://status.net. We may revise this Policy from time to time. The revised Policy is effective upon posting to this website.
